<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anubis</title>
    <link>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/</link>
    <description>Anubis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://<userlab27>.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Khibiny Mountains</title>
      <link>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/post/k/k/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/post/k/k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Khibiny Massif are the highest mountains of the Kola Peninsula, a large peninsula extending from northern Russia into the Barents and White seas. The total land area of the peninsula is approximately 100,000 square kilometres (39,000 sq mi). It is rich in minerals due to the removal of a layer of soil during the last ice age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Khibiny Massif is of oval shape of about 1,300 km2. and occupies the central part of the peninsula at a relative elevation of 900–1000 m above the surrounding plain. The mountains are not particularly high; the two highest peaks are the Yudychvumchorr, which stands 1,201 metres (3,940 ft), and the Chasnachorr, which stands 1,191 metres (3,907 ft). The average elevation is 1,116 metres (3,661 ft). The mountains form the shape of a horseshoe topped by a high plateau, drained by a series of deep canyons. The peaks are of plateau type, with steep slopes, with glaciers, icefields and snowfields in some places. The overall terrain is alpine tundra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second, and similar mountain range of the Kola Peninsula, the Lovozero Tundras, is located about 5 km east from the easternmost point of Khibiny, separated from it by Lake Umbozero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Khibiny range is extremely rich in minerals, mainly apatite and nepheline ores. 477 valid minerals have been reported and 108 of those are type localities or minerals first described in the Khibiny. The range is also seismically active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khibiny mountains are mostly uninhabited, except for one of the world&amp;rsquo;s richest mineral quarries. One of the minerals discovered there is reported to have a potential as a nuclear waste radioactivity absorbent. By the foot of the massif the cities of Apatity and Kirovsk are situated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khibiny National Park</title>
      <link>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/post/n/n/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/post/n/n/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Khibiny National Park protects a mountainous region of taiga and tundra on the Khibiny Mountains and Lovozero Massif of the western Kola Peninsula in northwestern Russia.The mountains contain commercially important minerals, and the park&amp;rsquo;s borders reflect the need to balance three uses - protection of the unique natural environment, recreation (hiking in the summer, skiing in the winter), and industrial mining. The park was officially created in 2018, and is located in the districts of Kirovsk and Olenegorsk Murmansk Oblast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;topography&#34; &gt;Topography
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#topography&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surrounded by low plains, the varied terrain of the mountains supports high biodiversity. The mountain range itself is a circle about 40 km across, with Lake Imandra on the western border, and Lake Umbozero on the eastern. The park has two sections - a west sector and east sector of approximately equal size and central valley corridor that is not in the protected zone.Across Lake Imandra to the west is the Lapland Biosphere Reserve. Elevations in the park range from 130 to 1,196 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ecoregion-and-climate&#34; &gt;Ecoregion and climate
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ecoregion-and-climate&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;he park is at the northern edge of the Scandinavian and Russian taiga ecoregion, only a few kilometers south of the official transition to the Kola Peninsula tundra ecoregion.The climate of the ecoregion is Subarctic climate, without dry season (Köppen climate classification Subarctic climate (Dfc)). This climate is characterized by mild summers (only 1-3 months above 10 °C (50.0 °F)) and cold, snowy winters (coldest month below −3 °C (26.6 °F)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;plants-and-animals&#34; &gt;Plants and animals
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#plants-and-animals&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ground cover in the park is 62% grassland, 27% forest, 8% bare rock, and the remaining 3% shrub cover or water.Species diversity is high, as there are different altitude zones, different landform types, and mixing of species in the transition zone between Arctic and taiga flora zones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Khibiny Mountains</title>
      <link>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Khibiny Massif are the highest mountains of the Kola Peninsula, a large peninsula extending from northern Russia into the Barents and White seas. The total land area of the peninsula is approximately 100,000 square kilometres (39,000 sq mi). It is rich in minerals due to the removal of a layer of soil during the last ice age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more and contribute on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khibiny_Mountains&#34;&gt;Khibiny&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Хибины</title>
      <link>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/about.ru/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/about.ru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Массив Хибины - самые высокие горы Кольского полуострова, большого полуострова, простирающегося с севера России до Баренцева и Белого морей. Общая площадь полуострова составляет приблизительно 100 000 квадратных километров (39 000 кв. миль). Они богаты полезными ископаемыми из-за удаления слоя почвы во время последнего ледникового периода.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Узнать больше на &lt;a href=&#34;https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%A5%D0%B8%D0%B1%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%8B&#34;&gt;Хибины&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://&lt;userlab27&gt;.github.io/%3Ckn%3E/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
